# — TYLER MITCHELL .—

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

#### CONTACT

317.426.0847

tylermitchellisawesome@gmail.com

(INSERT WEBSITE HERE)

#### **PROFILE**

 $\operatorname{Hi}$  , I'm Tyler. I create new things and connect you to solutions through automation.

In my work, I believe the best way to innovate is to combine ever-growing experiences with the best tools in the industry and to not shy away from the work. A crucial part of innovation is making sure any solution is sustainable in its implementation. I consider these factors as I forge new paths forward in the areas of quality control, software development, and process improvement.

I find myself gravitating towards industry research and game design in my spare time. I participate in Global Game Jam, among other game jams, throughout the year. I also enjoy plenty of board games, Magic: The Gathering, No Man's Sky, and playing with my cat, Beatrice.

The tools I use are JavaScript, C#, HTML5, CSS, NodeJS, and Unity.

#### **SKILLS**

- ANALYTICAL THINKER
- ADAPTABLE
- ORGANIZED
- DEPENDABLE
- SELF-MOTIVATED
- EFFICIENT

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **IUPUI**

2008-2012

Computer Science

Completed 90 credit hours towards a B.S. degree, but left due to a family health emergency.

#### INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

#### **Inventory Control Specialist**

Pitney Bowes, June 2019-December 2019

- \* Generated optimal walking paths to fix unknowns with Excel
- \* Added and removed floor locations to improve warehouse workflow
- \* Performed cycle counts on Order Picker

## **Quality Auditor**

*UNFI*, May 2017 – February 2019

- \* Built auditing software to automatically detect mis-picks and document additional quality errors such as product hanging over pallets and liquids stacked on their sides.
- \* Audited all outbound processes, including replenishment, picking, loading, and invoicing.

#### Freelance Software Developer

Self-Employed, May 2017- June 2018

- \* Created educational minigames in Unity3D and C# to aid in teaching AP Biology.
- \* Combined the concepts of personality theory and microeconomics to assist in creating a sociological simulation game to help students maximize social cohesion and economic productivity by using JavaScript (ES6), NodeJS, HTML, and CSS

## ICQA Developer (Tier IV Associate)

Amazon, April 2016 – April 2017

#### Tier I Associate

March 2015 - April 2016

- \* Increased departmental efficiency with Excel through one-on-one education and workflow demonstrations
- \* Crafted new applications to streamline internal processes, including inventory storage, safety communications, and Excel report automation

# Unity 3D / Android Developer

Vision Three Creative, LLC, March 2014 – October 2014

- \* Constructed the user interface of a custom Android application used to control an embedded medical device
- \* Updated and maintained applications for a large client base
- \* Originated demonstrations of AR and VR applications for clients

# Freelance Software Developer

Self-Employed, May 2011 - July 2014

- \* Developed AI and pathfinding solutions for all game enemies in Dreamland Delivery using A\* and B-Splines in C# for Puca Studios
- \* Produced educational Flash games for the Indianapolis Children's Museum